SHIWANSHU MISHRA

DevOps Engineer

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Bilingual DevOps Engineer with background designing, testing, and implementing infrastructure and applications, I focus on scalability and performance. Skilled with 3 years of experience to deploy the laaS based & Container based application using CI/CD tools and also identify and fix bugs in code.

WORK HISTORY

DevOps Engineer, 01/2020 - Current

Taikisha Engineering India Pvt. Ltd., Gurgaon, India

- Actively Deploy, Manage, Improve and monitor cloud infrastructure on AWS, EC2, S3, and RD5, and Route53, Cloud-Formation scaling.
- · Experienced in Python and Linux shell scripting.
- Experienced with container orchestration system such as Docker.
- Experienced in server side technologies such as Nginx
- Server Automation with Terraform and Ansible or other configuration management tools.
- Participate in deploying, automating, maintaining and managing AWS cloud based production system.

DevOps System Engineer, 03/2018 - 11/2018 **GSM Enterprises Pvt. Ltd**, Bangalore, India

- Participate automation end user testing and smoke and sanity testing, and db testing.
- Design the Automation task and setup CI/CD pipeline with jenkins and bitbucket.
- Testing and deployment of the automation script using selenium framework python and Django.
- Involved in designing of Linux server environments for developers and testers, supporting them, and documenting procedures for IT support.

QA Test Engineer, 06/2017 - 03/2018

Techonlabs India pvt Itd., Gurgaon, India

- Developed and executed comprehensive test plans and workforce breakdown structures for complete systems.
- Wrote high-quality test cases and scripts for use with selenium-java automation software
- Created comprehensive test plans, test scripts and use cases to support testing objectives.
- Involved in Manual Testing and Automation Testing using Java Selenium with TestNg and Hubrid, BDD Framework.
- Good exposure in the Agile methodology and test case abbreviations.
- Work over Smoke, Sanity, Functional and Non-Functional, GUI Testing in Mobile App and Web App.
- Performed Back-end testing using SQL queries to validate the data in the back-end Database.

- Gandhi Nagar, Gurgaon, India 122001
- 931 838 9711
- shiwanshusharma22@yahoo.

SKILLS

- Version Control: Git, GitHub
- Docke
- Amazon Web Services (EC2, S3, IAM, Route53, CloudFormation)
- Scripting Languages: Pythdninux Bash
- CI/CD (Jenkins)
- Ansible , Terraform
- HTML, CSS
- Agile/Scrum Methodology

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Technology, Computer Engineering Technology, 06/2016 ITM University - Gwalior, MP

High School Diploma, 06/2013 Govt. Polytechnic Collage - Gurgaon

CERTIFICATIONS

 Certified Software Tester, - Nov 2016